<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DUETBooklet</string>
    <string name="dept">Departments</string>
    <string name="para">A parse pictorially shows how the start symbol of a grammar derives a string in the language. If nonterminal A has a production A-> XYZ, then a parse tree may have an interior node labeled A with three children labeled X,Y and Z , from left to right.A parse pictorially shows how the start symbol of a grammar derives a string in the language. If nonterminal A has a production A-> XYZ, then a parse tree may have an interior node labeled A with three children labeled X,Y and Z , from left to right.</string>
    <string-array name="departments">
        <item>Department of Computer Science and Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Mechanical Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Textile Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Architecture</item>
        <item>Department of Industrial and Production Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Civil Engineering</item>
        <item>Department of Food Engineering</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="programme">
        <item>Under Graduate Programme</item>
        <item>Post Graduate Programme</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="UndergraduateRulesAndRegulations">
        <item>1. Definitions</item>
        <item>2. Faculties </item>
        <item>3. Departments</item>
        <item>3.1 Degree-Awarding Departments</item>
        <item>3.2 Teaching Departments</item>
        <item>4. Degrees Offered</item>
        <item>5. Student Admission</item>
        <item>7. Academic Calendar</item>
        <item>8. Duration of Programme and Course Structure</item>
        <item>9. Course Designation and Numbering Systems</item>
        <item>10. Type of Courses</item>
        <item>10.1 Core Courses</item>
        <item>10.2 Pre-requisite Courses</item>
        <item>10.3 Optional Courses</item>
        <item>10.4 Non Credit Courses</item>
        <item>11. Departmental Monitoring Committee and Students’ Advise</item>
        <item>11.1 Departmental Monitoring Committee</item>
        <item>11.2 Students’ Adviser</item>
        <item>11.3 Teacher Student Contact</item>
        <item>12. Course Registration and its Procedure </item>
        <item>12.1 Credit Limit in a Semester</item>
        <item>12.2 Pre-condition for Registration</item>
        <item>12.3 Course Adjustment Procedure</item>
        <item>12.4 Withdrawal from a Semester</item>
        <item>13. Striking off the Names and Readmission</item>
        <item>14. Grading System, Calculation of GPA and Cumulative GPA, and Conversion of Marks</item>
        <item>14. Grading System, Calculation of GPA and Cumulative GPA, and Conversion of Marks</item>
        <item>14.1 Grading System</item>
        <item>14.2 Calculation of GPA and Cumulative GPA</item>
        <item>14.2 Calculation of GPA and Cumulative GPA</item>
        <item>14.3 Conversion of Grade into Marks</item>
        <item>15. Distribution of Marks</item>
        <item>15.1 The distribution of marks for a given course will be as follows</item>
        <item>15.2</item>
        <item>15.3 Basis for distribution of marks in class participation and attendance will be as follows</item>
        <item>15.4</item>
        <item>16. Class Tests, Quizzes and Spot Tests</item>
        <item>17. Earned Credits</item>
        <item>18. Measures for Helping Academically Weak Students</item>
        <item>19. Honours, Dean’s List and University Gold Medal</item>
        <item>19.1 Honours</item>
        <item>19.2 Dean’s List</item>
        <item>19.3 University Gold Medal</item>
        <item>20. Student Classification</item>
        <item>21. Probation and Suspension</item>
        <item>22. Minimum Earned Credits and GPA Requirements for  Obtaining Degree</item>
        <item>23. Time Limits for Completion of B. Sc. Engineering Degree</item>
        <item>24. Industrial/Professional Training Requirements</item>
        <item>25. Application for Graduation and Award of Degree</item>
        <item>26. Absence during Semester</item>
        <item>27. Review Courses</item>
        <item>28. Special Examination</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="year">
        <item>First Year Second Semester</item>
        <item>Second Year First Semester</item>
        <item>Second Year Second Semester</item>
        <item>Third Year First Semester</item>
        <item>Third Year Second Semester</item>
        <item>Fourth Year First Semester</item>
        <item>Fourth Year Second Semester</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="yearpost">
        <item>First Year</item>
        <item>Second Year</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="menu">
        <item>Booklet</item>
        <item>Act</item>
        <item>Rules</item>
        <item>About</item>

    </string-array>
    <string name="cseh">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</string>
    <string name="cse">
        In order to prepare potential and productive persons in industry, academia, as well as in government sector, in the undergraduate and postgraduate programs of the department of CSE of DUET, an excellent environment of teaching, learning, and research in computing and IT has been maintained from the very past. In particular, to perform world-class research in selected areas of computing (such as Speech Signal Processing, Advanced Microprocessor Architecture, Reliable and Low Power Multi-core Processor Design, Data Warehouse and Mining, Operating Systems, Wireless Network, Networking, Image Processing and Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence and Neural Network, Algorithm Design and Analysis). The mission of the department is to earn reputation nationally and internationally for research in different areas. The faculty members are enriched in diversified fields and are involved in updated research work. To provide quality, cutting-edge educational experiences, the department aims to provide students with strong conceptual foundations, and also expose them to the forefront of the developments in the field of computing. The department’s other vision includes providing state-of-the-art computer education and training to all students at DUET to bring them to the level of knowledge and ability.
        The Department of Computer Science and Engineering maintains well-equipped laboratories for graduate and undergraduate research work. The laboratories are: (1) Software lab, (2) Network lab, (3) Digital Electronics lab, and (4) Multimedia lab. In addition, a BdREN datacenter maintained by the CSE department has the most advanced servers, routers, and switches.
        Scope of Computer Science and Engineering
        The academic objectives of the Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) are to provide outstanding education and research programs that can:Promote a philosophy of learning with the development of a computer science/engineering student body to be prepared for their specific profession, for advanced studies and careers in research with multidisciplinary knowledge.Provide a stimulating academic research environment for individuals who would be capable to work in both industry and academia, and would be the leaders in the demonstration of professional skills and in the development of new technology for the benefit of society.
        For more Information
        Head
        Department of Computer Science and Engineering
        Dhaka University of Engineering and Technology, Gazipu
        Gazipur-1700
        Phone : +88-02-9204711, +88-02-9204734-53, Ext. 3201 (Off.)
        Fax : +88-02-9204701, +88-02-9204702
        E-mail: head_cse@duet.ac.bd
        Web : www.duet.ac.bd/cse
    </string>

    <string name="eeeh">Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering</string>
    <string name="eee">
    Electricity is the most conducive part of the modern technology based life. Even all other technology, which is thought as munificent to human life, is also electricity or electronically controlled. The professional activities of electrical engineers directly affect the everyday lives of most of the world’s population. They are responsible for the design and development of radio and television transmitters and receivers, telephone networks and switching systems, computer systems, and electric power generation and distribution. Within the broad scope of these systems, the electrical engineer is concerned with a challenging and diverse array of design and development problems. The students who earn a B. Sc. Engineering degree from the department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering will be involved in a variety of electrical and electronic problems in the course of their careers.
    Scope of Electrical and Electronic Engineering
    The Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering plays a major role in the development of science and technology. This role is more important as the use of electronic devices and electric power is increasing in many technologies, such as VLSI, lasers, material processing, optoelectronic devices, robotics, communication, computer technology, micro-machine, electric power supply, various types of control systems etc. Since the areas covered by Electrical and Electronic Engineering are increasing, the Department provides a broad curriculum to its students to adequately address those issues. Hence The students can choose their educational program according to their interests. They can choose a program that is partly related to electronic devices, electronic applications, and/or computer and communication. Besides the theoretical knowledge, intensive care is also given so that an engineer becomes pragmatic in terms of his/her respective area of specialization. In addition, the Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering of DUET, Gazipur offers postgraduate studies and research for higher degree leading to M. Sc. Engg., M. Engg. and Ph. D. To reciprocate such venture, the department offers financial assistance to the brilliant students. The Department is also incarnated with other activities, such as, expert level training on the appropriate field for the faculty members to develop human resources, consulting different organizations to facilitate them and exchanging knowledge with different national and international universities, etc.
    For more Information
    Head
    Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering
    Dhaka University of Engineering and Technology, Gazipur
    Gazipur-1700
    Phone : +88-02-9204709, +88-02-9204734-53, Ext. 3011 (Off.)
    Fax : +88-02- 9204709, +88-02- 9204702
    E-mail: Head_eee@duet.ac.bd
    Web : www.duet.ac.bd/eee
    </string>
    <string name="meh">Department of Mechanical Engineering </string>
    <string name="me">
        Scope of Electrical and Electronic Engineering
    The Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering plays a major role in the development of science and technology. This role is more important as the use of electronic devices and electric power is increasing in many technologies, such as VLSI, lasers, material processing, optoelectronic devices, robotics, communication, computer technology, micro-machine, electric power supply, various types of control systems etc. Since the areas covered by Electrical and Electronic Engineering are increasing, the Department provides a broad curriculum to its students to adequately address those issues. Hence The students can choose their educational program according to their interests. They can choose a program that is partly related to electronic devices, electronic applications, and/or computer and communication. Besides the theoretical knowledge, intensive care is also given so that an engineer becomes pragmatic in terms of his/her respective area of specialization. In addition, the Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering of DUET, Gazipur offers postgraduate studies and research for higher degree leading to M. Sc. Engg., M. Engg. and Ph. D. To reciprocate such venture, the department offers financial assistance to the brilliant students. The Department is also incarnated with other activities, such as, expert level training on the appropriate field for the faculty members to develop human resources, consulting different organizations to facilitate them and exchanging knowledge with different national and international universities, etc.
    For more Information
    Head
    </string>
    <string name="csetext">Department of Computer Science and Engineering
Undergraduate Curriculum

Syllabus  Session (2015-2016)
1st Year 1st Semester (Exempted)
Sl.	Course No.	Course Title	Cr.
1	Math-141	Mathematics – I	3
2	Ph-141	Physics – I	3
3	Ph-142	Physics – I Sessional	1.5
4	Ch-141	Chemistry-I	3
5	Ch-142	Chemistry-I Sessional	1.5
6	CSE-115	Computer Fundamentals	3
7	CSE-116	Computer Fundamentals Sessional	1.5
8	Hum-141	Government and Sociology	4
Total	20.5
 
1st Year 2nd Semester
Sl.	Course No.	Course Title	Cr.
1	CSE-1121	Structured Programming Language	4
2	CSE-1122	Structured Programming Language Sessional	1.5
3	 CSE-1823	Digital Logic and System Design	3
4	CSE-1824	Digital Logic and System Design Sessional	0.75
5	CSE-1124	Drawing and CAD Project Sessional	0.75
6	Math-1421	Mathematics – II	4
7	Ph-1423	Physics – II	4
8	Ph-1424	Physics – II Sessional	0.75
9	Hum-1427	English and Economics	3
Total	21.75
</string>

    <string name="title_activity_me_first_year_first_semester">MeFirstYearFirstSemester</string>

</resources>
